{\fn標楷體\fe136\fscx200\fscy200\an5\b0\bord2\c&H00FF00&\3c&HFF00FF&\2a&HFF&\4a&HFF&\pos(192,70)\K250}廁 零 手 位
{\fn標楷體\fe136\fscx200\fscy200\an5\b0\bord2\c&H00FF00&\3c&HFF00FF&\2a&HFF&\4a&HFF&\pos(192,120)\K250}所 食 機 置
{\fn標楷體\fe136\fscx200\fscy200\an5\b0\bord2\c&H00FF00&\3c&HFF00FF&\2a&HFF&\4a&HFF&\pos(192,170)\K250}先 備 關 坐
{\fn標楷體\fe136\fscx200\fscy200\an5\b0\bord2\c&H00FF00&\3c&HFF00FF&\2a&HFF&\4a&HFF&\pos(192,220)\K250}上 妥 掉 定
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe134\fscx290\fscy290\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H3399CC&\3c&HFFFFFF&\1a&HFF&\2a&HFF&\4a&HFF&\pos(195,200)\fad(500,0)\t(0,1500,\1a&H00&)\t(1000,4000,\3a&HFF&)}特效卓著
{\fnMonotype Corsiva\fe0\fscx220\fscy220\an5\b1\fsp4\bord4\blur5\shad0\1a&HFF&\pos(192,55)\fad(0,1200)}WJ-MAFIA
{\fnSimHei\fe134\fscx180\fscy180\an5\b1\bord0\shad0\c&H007050&\3c&H000000&\pos(192,220)\fad(1000,1000)\t(2000,2000,\blur5\bord2.5\3c&H00FFFF&)}譯者自填
In today's protests against
抗議政府撲滅蟑螂行動表現無能的
the government's.
大遊行剛剛結束
Organizers say 300,000 attended
主辦方宣稱遊行人數超過三十萬人
but police numbers were at 50,000.
警方則表示約有五萬名市民參加遊行
A government spokesman said
政府發言人指
an ad hoc committee has been formed.
已經成立緊急專案小組應付蟑螂災情
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe134\fscx200\fscy250\an2\b0\bord2\shad0\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&H000000&\move(192,0,192,160,0,1600)\fad(4000,1000)}Kwun Tong
but with no results yet; Hong Kongers are...
但是至今仍沒有有效對策
a month after the Big Roach Disaster...
因為今日是蟑螂大災難發生後的整一個月
In a reconstruction project in Kwun Tong
在觀塘舊區重建工程中
an illegal roach farm was accidentally destroyed.
意外破壞了一個非法蟑螂養殖場
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&HFF4400&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(130,10)\fad(1500,1000)}266kms North of Kuala Lumpur
Taiping Prison
Countless roaches have infested Hong Kong
導致數目難以估計的蟑螂飛到香港各區
for a month but the government can't help.
事發已經一個月政府依然束手無策
The incident has attracted international attention.
事件已經引起國際關注
But roaches multiply faster than they can be killed.
但滅蟲的速度遠遠比不上蟑螂繁殖的速度
Roaches have paralysed financial operations.
蟑螂癱瘓了香港金融貿易的正常運作
Hong Kong is finished.
香港完蛋啦
It's not up to you whether Hong Kongs is finished.
香港是否完蛋，輪不到你說
The city has lost
估計這幾個小時
$2 billion in a few hours
香港已損失超過二十億港幣
Hong Kong is really finished!
嘩！那香港真是完蛋啦！
TWO THUMBS UP!
TWO THUMBS UP !
What does that mean?
甚麼意思呀？
It's English.
英文
Don't you know that?
不認識嗎？
Too powerful to have friends.
就是勁到沒朋友
Too powerful for words.
勁到沒話說
What is "too powerful for words"?
甚麼叫勁到沒話說
Assault, or robbery?
打人呀？還是會打劫？
It still fits perfectly.
還是這麼合身
I haven't changed at all.
真的一點都沒變
I still have a model's physique.
身材依然是像模特
You haven't changed
你沒變
but the whole world has changed.
不過這個世界全變了
You don't know the world
你不認識這個世界
and it doesn't know you.
這個世界也不認識你
Only you know yourself!
（閩南語）只有你自己認自己
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx150\fscy150\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&HCCFFFF&\3c&H777777&\pos(192,0)\fad(0,0)}EXIT
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe134\fscx150\fscy150\an8\b0\bord2\shad0\c&HCCFFFF&\3c&H777777&\pos(192,20)\fad(0,0)}出口
Is that necessary?
喂？有必要嗎？
Escorted in here.
進來又押
And now, escorted out?
現在出又押
Not everyone can take this step!
邁出去的這一步，不是每個人都邁得出去
And.
還有
It is not "Too Jump Up".
不是 "TOO JUMP UP"
It should be "Two Thumbs Up".
是  "TWO THUMBS UP"
Let me tell you,
我告訴你
if I come in again I'm a rotten egg.
我要是再進來，我就是龜孫子
There is no more 39633 in this world.
這個世界不會有39633
There is only me, Lucifer.
只有一個人叫盧西發，就是我！
You can call me Big F.
給面子就叫聲發哥
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx150\fscy200\an2\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H00AACC&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(192,144)\fad(0,0)}16 Months Ago
Why does this look so familiar?
怎麼那麼眼熟
Are you from Hong Kong?
你是不是香港人來的
It's an emergency unit vehicle, EU.
衝鋒車嘛
Old ones are repurposed as school busses.
壞了就賣過來作校巴
The kids wore out the left door.
左門整天被小孩子拉，拉壞了
That's $2,000; there's a market for them.
兩千塊一個，有價有市
Think about it back in Hong Kong.
回到香港考慮一下
Having come out of this door
出了這個門
I want that door?
還想那個門
Of course to do a major job.
當然做一件大事
TWO THUMBS UP!
TWO THUMBS UP
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HBB5500&\move(145,10,-45,10)\fad(0,0)}The alley south of
266 Boundary Street
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an5\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000033&\3c&H005555&\move(320,60,300,0)\fad(0,0)}Nightclub Back Alley
Hair Salon
Look at this.
先看看
Great! It's the same as before.
很好呀！還跟以前一模一樣
You see.
是吧？
Just a bit younger.
就是年輕了點
Ready, Big F.
搞定了發哥
Come again.
有時間再來啊發哥
Hello, Crazy B? Big F is back.
喂！寶哥，發哥回來了
He didn't pay for his blow-dry.
他還是吹頭不給錢
I'm so unlucky.
你說是不是倒霉了這次
It's only about $100.
一百幾十塊的
You can't ask for it from him!
你跟他收啊？
Don't treat your buddies like dirt!
兄弟當契弟啊
A citizen has called in a lead.
有市民舉報稱
Roach farm boss BK Cheung has been found
在鹿頸發現導致香港變成蟑螂之都的
in Luk Keng; He made Hong Kong a city of roaches.
蟑螂養殖場負責人張寶強
Please call the police if you see BK Cheung.
警方呼籲市民如果發現張寶強請立即報警
Okay! I'll pay for the last two tickets!
好！還有兩位！我給了！
It's full, let's go!
齊人，開車！
Hello, Crazy B?
喂！阿寶呀？
Yes, did you know.
是啊，你知不知道
Big F is back.
阿發回來了
He's finally back.
他終於回來
He paid for two people.
他還一個人給兩個人車錢
That's just a few coins.
十塊八塊
- Give him his change!     - Okay!
-你不找給他？  -行啦！
Don't treat your buddies like dirt!
兄弟當契弟？
We're full, let's go!
總之齊人開車
齊人開車！
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an2\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H6644FF&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(300,260)\fad(0,400)}Ngau Tarn Mei
Northeastern Yuen Long
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx120\fscy120\an2\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H00CCCC&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(320,260)\fad(200,1000)}Halloween
October 31
The EU after us is not a real police vehicle.
追我們這輛警車的不是警車
People shooting at us are also not cops.
開槍射我們的警察也不是警察
I've never seen a cop shoot an AK-47.
你甚麼時候見過警察開AK-47的
Ours is also not a real EU.
我們這輛警車又不是警車
It's a Toyota Coaster, 2003 model
是豐田Coaster，零三年的車
with over 500,000 km.
五十幾萬公里
For 10 years, its route is Kwun Tong Road,
這十年，來來去去都在觀塘道
Prince Edward Road West, Argyle Street, Sai Yee Street.
太子道西，亞皆老街，洗衣街
It's a Kwun Tong - Mong Kok red minibus.
它是一輛從觀塘去旺角的紅色小巴
16 minutes ago,
十六分鐘前
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx120\fscy120\an2\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H00CCCC&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(330,220)\fad(200,1000)}16 Minutes Ago
When we attempted robbery in our "EU",
我們這輛冒充衝鋒車的小巴動手的時候
we ran into another gang with the same idea,
居然碰到另一幫扮警察開假警車打劫的賊
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an7\b1\bord0.01\shad0\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(260,10)\fad(0,0)}" Identical Robbery Tactics "
Identical robbery tactics!
打劫也會撞橋！
We never imagined after a few kilometers
哪會想到十幾公里後
this minibus would think it's a real EU
這輛小巴當自己是警車
and we would think we were real cops.
我們幾兄弟也把自己當真警察
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx200\fscy150\an8\b1\bord0\shad0\c&HFFFFFF&\2a&HFF&\3a&HFF&\4a&HFF&\pos(192,5)\fad(0,0)}Real Cops
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx150\fscy200\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\fsp1\c&H0099FF&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(192,200)\fad(200,0)}正邪保齡球場
Big F...
發…
Big F, I've waited 16 years for you!
發…我等了你十六年！
Shut up, listen to me!
別說，聽我說！
I've been refining a plan for 16 years.
我有個點子想了十六年
A decades-old plan
十幾年前的點子
it will be out-dated.
不會過時了吧？
Marvelous idea are never out-dated.
好點子是不會過時的
Then we'll see if anyone else has come up with it.
那要看有沒有第二人想到了
It's not easy to come up with a marvellous idea.
好點子沒那麼容易想的
Disguise ourselves as cops and rob.
扮警察打劫
None of us here
我們這幾個人
look like a cop.
沒一個像警察的
How many reals cops look like cops?
那你說警察哪裡像警察
Those are the real cops.
就是不像警察的才是警察
Drive an Emergency Unit.
開輛衝鋒車
Wear a uniform.
穿上警服
Anyone will think you're a cop.
誰都當是你警察
I think he's right.
我覺得他說的對
But where can we get an EU?
但是去哪裡找輛警車回來
I know where to buy one.
我知道哪裡有得買
Wherever you can buy one you can sell one.
哪裡有得買哪兒就有得賣
Wherever you can sell one you can steal one.
哪裡有得賣哪兒就有得偷
So we steal one; what do we rob?
偷到了，劫甚麼？
Bank, gas station, goldsmith shops,
銀行，油站，金鋪，便利店，解款車
convenience stores, whatever you like.
你喜歡甚麼就劫甚麼！
People use credit cards, debit cards and cash cards
VISA , MASTER，銀聯，AE，八達通
no one uses cash!
Cash就沒有啦！
There are closed-circuit cameras everywhere!
滿街都是閉路電視
You can't get shit!
屎你都沒得吃！
What's wrong with you, Crazy B?
你怎麼了呀，阿寶
We're robbers; we have to rob!
我們做賊當然要打劫啦
No knife? Find a brick,
沒刀子拿磚頭
rob something, buy an AK, trade up to a bazooka.
劫到錢買AK然後換大炮
If you eat shit, eat the smelliest.
吃屎就吃最臭的
If you rob, rob the biggest place.
打劫，就要劫個最大的
TWO THUMBS UP!
TWO THUMBS UP !
Yes, you are powerful!
你真是夠猛呀！
Everyone eats food and shits poop.
個個都是吃飯拉屎的
It's powerful to eat poop and shit food.
吃屎拉飯更猛
If you're so powerful
你這麼猛
why don't you go eat shit?
你怎麼不去吃屎？
Are you in this or not?
你是不是不玩呀？
If you're not, we'll go on ourselves.
你不玩，我們自己玩
Sit down...
喂，坐下…
I'm not playing-
我不玩
What's wrong?
幹甚麼？
What? Give it back! It's very expensive.
幹甚麼？很貴的，還給我！
You still owe me for your last blow-dry!
你上次吹頭還沒給錢，我告訴你！
I'll pay when we get money from robbing.
劫到錢，就還給你呀！
I'll even pay for your hairdo forever, okay?
你的頭，我包了行不行？
I'm on your side right now!
我挺你！我現在挺你呀！
We are robbers.
我們是賊嘛
It is right that we rob.
打劫就對了
But we must share the same goal
齊心才可以
from the start, do you understand?
召集兄弟都要齊心，你明不明白
Are we all here?
人齊嗎？
If we're full, let's go.
人齊可以開車
Call me when you have everyone.
人齊打給我
You have reached a message service.
你已經被接到留言服務
Please leave a message after the beep.
請嗶一聲之後留下你的口信
We will notify the recipient as soon as possible.
然後掛起電話，我們會盡快通知機主
Scumbag!
混蛋！
Where did you go? Scumbag!
你死哪兒去了？混蛋！
What weapons do you have?
拿甚麼傢伙啊？
Plane? Cannons?
飛機大炮呀！
You were gone for days.
幾天都看不到人
You treat your buddies like dirt.
兄弟當契弟
Crazy B, bad news!
喪寶哥出事了
You were right not to come.
你不來就對
Big F left on the speedboat.
發哥坐快艇走了
But he said you treat your buddies like dirt.
不過他說你兄弟當契弟
Crazy B, where are you?
喪寶哥你在哪裡？
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx150\fscy150\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H003399&\3c&H000000&\pos(192,10)\fad(200,0)}Miss calls: 65
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx150\fscy150\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H003399&\3c&H000000&\pos(192,10)\fad(0,0)}Miss calls: 66
Where were you? It all went bad!
去哪裡了？出大事了！
Big F had to leave town
發哥跑路了
he said you treat your buddies like dirt.
他說你兄弟當契弟
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000000&\3c&HFFBB77&\pos(140,10)\fad(0,0)}Big F
Answer?
Teat your buddies like dirt...
兄弟當契弟啊
I didn't! I didn't!
我沒有！我沒有啊！
Teat your buddies like dirt...
兄弟當契弟
I didn't!
我沒有
Those scumbags locked me up for days.
我被那些混蛋關了幾天
I didn't treat my buddies like dirt.
我沒兄弟當契弟
Bowling Alley...
保齡球場…
Nasty Daughter.
死丫頭
You don't even greet your father.
老爸也不叫一聲！
Calling to check to see if I'm at work?
一大早打來檢查我有沒有上班嗎？
It's been two weeks and seven days.
兩個禮拜零七天啦
That boss is so friendly to me.
那個老闆不知道跟我有多好
You're calling each other buddies, Mr Chou?
又稱兄道弟啊周先生
That's good!
那就好啦
Because I don't want to find you another job.
我也不想再幫你找工作了
We have to steal corpses.
我們要劫屍
Some people
有的屍體
remove a corpses innards,
被人把心肝脾肺腎挖出來
stuff money in them.
裡面塞滿了錢
And fill the corpse with money.
他們把錢塞進屍體裡面
They use these cross-border services
他們就是用這種跨境的運屍車
to bring dirty money into Hong Kong.
把黑錢走私來香港
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx150\fscy150\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H00FFFF&\3c&H000088&\pos(192,10)\fad(0,0)}Cross-Border Corpse Transportation
Why? It's too expensive to live in Hong Kong!
為甚麼？因為香港實在太貴！
Many move back to their hometowns,
很多人搬回鄉下住
but insist on being buried in Hong Kong.
但是死就一定死回來香港
So more bodies need to be shipped.
所以跨境屍體就愈來愈多
With a system you can hide anything.
有組織，會掩飾
Crematoriua use this to move money.
有火葬場，根本就是用來走私黑錢
So now we've gone beyond robbery.
所以我們這一次已經不是打劫這麼簡單
We're not just doing this for money,
我們不是為錢
but to uphold justice!
是替天行道！
If we don't rob those scumbags
不劫那些混蛋
we are not doing justice to heaven
我們對不對得起老天？
nor to our ancestors.
對不對得那些先人？
They will be buried with an incomplete corpse!
死無全屍呀！
Imagine!
你們想想
If they did this to your mother,
如果是挖你老媽
Your father, your brother,
挖你老爸，挖你兄弟
Wouldn't you do something about it?
你們做不做事？
In the day, you were a champion car racer
當年，一代車神
nicknamed "Not Looking back".
外號「有後波」
Now you drive a minibus.
現在開小巴
"Not strating up".
打不著火
It's been so long, you must be used to it.
你憋了這麼久是不習慣了？
Used to what?
習慣甚麼！
Don't get used to it!
就是不讓習慣！
Why must four of us share a lane?
為甚麼四個人要打一條球道？
We should each take up four lanes!
我們應該一個人佔四條球道！
And you.
還有你
What about me? I'm okay.
我怎麼啦？我可以啊！
I style massage girls' hair in the alley,
幫那些按摩女在後巷裡做髮型，搞造型
What's wrong with that?
有甚麼問題啊？
You're cutting hair for streetwalkers.
給按摩女剪頭
No wonder your girlfriend keeps dumping you.
難怪你女朋友整天要甩你
We should do a major job.
我們幾兄弟做一票大的
Is that okay or not?
好不好？
- Okay?     - Okay!
-好不好？  -好！
Well, Crazy B?
怎麼樣阿寶？
Crazy B, how about what you owe me?
阿寶，你欠我那筆怎麼算？
How will you pay me back?
怎麼算呀？
What you owe me!
你欠我那筆
Excuse me, gentlemen.
不好意思，幾位
It's closing time!
收工啦！
Please pay this tab; thanks!
麻煩你們先結了這帳單，謝謝
It's $473.50.
四百七十三塊五
You have to chip in for a few hundred bucks!
幾百塊還要大家湊啊？
Here's mine...
我加點…
Shall I treat?
要不我請
You're too kind.
不要這麼客氣
I'll pay for this.
這點錢我付
Take it off my paycheck.
從我薪水扣不就行咯
In your dreams.
我扣你個頭
Have you worked here a month?
你做夠一個月沒有呀？
Must you talk like that?
要不要這麼說話？
I treat you as an elder brother.
我當你是大哥
You treat my buddies like dirt.
你卻當我的兄弟是契弟
If these are your buddies,
個個都稱兄道弟
then you deserve to be treated like dirt.
那就活該你做契弟
I quit!
兄弟，不幹了！
The sooner I die the sooner I am reincarnated.
早死早投胎
Steal that vehicle!
偷車！
The sooner we work the sooner we enjoy rewards.
早動手早享受！
That is a police car graveyard.
那個車場是警車的和合石墳場
All the Old,
舊的、壞的或者錯的車
dead EUs are brought here.
全部都會送來這個車場
Those police transport vehicles are all wrong!
那種警隊運輸車不止錯了，是全錯
The Traffic Department classifies
我告訴你車底架是工字架的
vehicles with an H-beam under the chassis
運輸署歸類作貨車
as trucks, not passenger vehicles.
根本不讓載人！
In the past, all police vehicles were illegal.
之前在街上行駛的警車全部都是非法的
You never thought law-breaking cops.
你不會想到警察犯法會這麼大搖大擺
Would be so bold, right?
不是吧？
You want to steal these?
偷這些？
The cops must keep records.
警察不會沒記錄吧？
I don't want to steal these.
當然不是偷這些
I just brought you to see them.
帶你們來看看而已
We've seen them, and all we can do is see them.
看過了，只剩一個「看」字
Now what?
那現在怎麼辦？
You might use more than your eyes...
看東西呢…
to see things...
未必是用眼睛看…
Robbers must have imagination...
做賊要有點想像力…
See...
看看
Do you see it now?
看沒看到
No guns? Make one.
沒槍就造
No vehicle? Soup one up!
沒車就改
We used to make AKs out of revolvers.
以前左輪改AK
Now, we transfrom a minibus into an EU.
今天小巴改警車
This is our 16-seater EU.
這輛就是我們十六座的衝鋒車
It sounds cool
聽起來好像很有型
but I don't know why it feels stupid.
不知道為甚麼隱約覺得有點蠢
Looking upside down at an upside down
反轉看著反轉的香港
Hong Kong, it should look right
應該是一樣的
but it seems strange!
但很陌生！
This fully-equipped,
我坐的這架加上裝備
7,800kg EU
有七千八百公斤的衝鋒車
fell down from a 16-meter flyover
在十六米的天橋上摔下來
and flipped 180 degrees!
一百八十度回轉！
My number 39633.
我的警察編號39633
My name is Tsui On Leung.
我叫徐安良，除暴安良的徐安良
Today is my first day back as 39633
今天是我做回39633
and in my uniform again.
重新穿回制服的第一天！
16 weeks ago,
十六個星期前
I was undercover in Operation.
我在反黑組代號「忘不了」
"Lost in Time".
的行動裡面做臥底
Aimed at gangsters
「忘不了」的目標是瓦解
controlling "Tin-Tong line".
控制「天塘線」的黑幫組織
The minibus line from.
「天塘線」就是由天水圍
Tin Shui Wai to Kwun Tong.
到觀塘的紅色小巴線
Out of uniform, I did not recognise myself.
不穿警察制服，我不認得自己
I didn't know if I was a cop or a bus driver.
我搞不清楚自己是警察還是小巴司機
Should I catch thieves with a gun
我究竟應該是持槍抓賊
or drive a bus and take on passengers?
還是開車載客
I couldn't take it, and went back to the station.
我受不了啦，決定調回警局
A gun, a wok, a minibus; which
持槍，拿鍋鏟，開小巴
do you think can help you catch thieves?
你覺得哪樣可以抓到賊呢？
You don't have to rely on a uniform.
抓賊不是靠衣服
It's not important what you wear.
穿甚麼不重要
He is my elder brother.
跟我說「穿甚麼不重要」的是我大哥
His undercover mission went on for three and three years.
他策劃過一個三年又三年的臥底行動
He thinks you can catch thieves whatever you wear.
他相信「抓賊不是靠制服」
My police cap is gone!
我的警帽不見了！
I never thought, by looking for the cap.
怎會想到，為了找回這頂警帽
I finally understood, 16 days later,
我在十六日之後終於明白
that one can look at the world upside down.
原來可以反轉看這個世界
Heroes have more than one angle.
原來，英雄不是只有一個角度
They are 360 degrees!
是三百六十度的！
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000077&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(75,170)\fad(0,0)}Double Star Junkyard
Where is the flipped-over EU?
師兄，翻了的那輛衝鋒車呢？
It was cleared by the vehicle pound and
那輛車何文田車輛扣留中心檢查過了
written off as a total loss; it's waiting to be junked.
報廢了，送去車場等著拆！
Have you seen my police cap?
有沒有見過我的警帽
My police cap is caught in the door.
我的警帽就夾在車門裡面
No!
沒有！
Fill out this form; apply for a new one.
填張表格再申請一頂啦！
No, that cap is important to me.
不行，這頂警帽對我來說很重要
My police cap and the door are gone.
我的警帽跟車門一起不見了
This isn't the only one missing a side door.
不止這輛警車沒了側門
That one is missing a back door.
有的警車沒了後門
32 parts have been dragged across here.
總共有三十二條零件拖過地面的痕跡
Six vehicles are missing doors,
六架警車不見了車門
some are missing hoods, bumpers,
還有的警車的前引擎蓋，保險杠
rearview mirror, wipers,
倒後鏡，雨刷不見了
mud guard, window grille, head and tail lights, siren lights,
沙板、鐵絲網、車頭同車尾燈、警號燈…
Put all these parts together.
丟了的警車零件，不多不少
And you get a complete EU vehicle!
剛好能組裝一輛衝鋒車！
They're stealing parts to make an EU!
偷零件，組裝假警車…
Who are these people?
他們究竟是甚麼人？
What do they want to do?
究竟想幹甚麼？
Criminals leaves clues at the scene.
罪犯會在犯案現場留下痕跡
Like you leave your smell on your clothes.
就好像穿過的衣服上面會有你的氣味！
The crime scene can speak.
犯罪現場會說話
It tells me, there were four people!
它告訴我，偷零件的是四個人！
Drawer, glove compartment, visor...
抽屜，櫃門，遮光板…
All 40 compartments in 20 EUs have been opened.
二十部警車四十個櫃桶全部打開過！
He takes every chance to find money.
他是一個不放過任何找到錢的機會的人
He is greedy; he'll do anything for money.
這個人貪得無厭，為了錢甚麼都做得出
Let's call this suspect.
假設這個疑犯叫做A !
"A" is the arrogant type of criminal.
A是狂妄型罪犯！
My police cap is caught in the door he stole.
我的警帽就夾在他偷去的門裡面
Unlike "A",
跟A不一樣
"B" has cleaner moves. He's a pro.
B的手法俐落，專業
Loves machines, experienced.
熱愛機械，有經驗
Kills roaches with
連殺蟑螂都用攝氏負七十五度的
spray chilled to -75J.
冷凍殺蟲劑
He uses his advantages in his crimes!
他利用專長來犯案！
A typical Professional Criminal!
他是典型的專業型罪犯
A dried moist wipe
乾了的濕紙巾
made to clean shoes.
專門用來擦鞋的
To be so picky about cleaning his shoes.
連擦鞋都這麼挑剔
C has high standards.
C是一個很講究的人
He is the perfectionist criminal.
他是完美型的罪犯！
There are two footprints on this poop
糞便上有兩個鞋印
facing in opposite directions.
一個向東一個向西
To step in poop on a 3.5 meter wide path
成三點五米闊的路都踩屎
twice...
還踩兩次
D either has vision problems, or
D，要麼眼睛有問題
chooses not to look at anything.
要麼就是目空一切
These 38 overlapping, chaotic footprints
這三十八個重疊、忽左忽右的鞋印
belong to the team's most loyal follower
反映了D沒主見、跟大隊
who has no opinions or ideas of his own!
他是團隊裡面最忠心的服從者！
It's done.
完成了
It's so difficult to be a thief.
做賊都這麼難
It's always difficult to do something well.
要做得好，甚麼都會難的
Why couldn't we use a can of white paint
為甚麼不用一罐白漆
and spray it white?
噴…噴白它
Write "Police" on it, and it's done.
然後寫警察兩個字，這就快啦！
All these steps! Are you stupid?
一塊一塊裝！是不是腦殘你們？
Spray it white, it's a white minibus.
噴白它，它始終是一架白色的小巴
Spray you black, you're a black thief.
噴黑你，你始終是個黑色的賊
So deep!
哇！高深！
We can snap off the shell, it will become a minibus again,
對，一會兒剝了殼立刻變回一輛小巴
and we can take paying passengers.   We'll make over $100, buddies!
還可以多跑幾趟多賺一百多塊啊，朋友
Don't you think we're missing something?
你們不覺我們少一樣東西嗎？
We don't have guns!
我們少的是槍啊！
But certainly not these.
但肯定不是這幾支
They're all rusty. Useless, like you!
全部生了銹，就像你一樣那麼沒用
I worked hard to keep these four guns.
喂！我很辛苦才保住這四支槍
Don't talk about the past any more.
夠了！不要再說以前的事了
We need guns to rob people.
我們打劫就需要槍
Police! Hands up!
警察！舉起手
You didn't say "Don't move".
你沒說別動兩個字！兄弟
Police! Don't move! Hands up!
警察！別動！舉起手！
How can I put my hands up if I don't move?
不動又怎樣舉起手呢？
Stupid!
真蠢
It works! We look the part.
可以啊！像啊！
Hey, we look better in these uniforms
喂！我們幾兄弟穿上制服
than real cops; come...
比很多真警察還帥，來…
I don't look like a cop,
看來看去我們都不像
what cop is has this much style?
真警察哪有這麼有型？
- Come...     - Let me to take the picture...
-來來來  -我來拍…
Cool!
型！
I don't like the way you look.
真是愈看你愈不順眼
Where did you come from, boy!
小子，你哪裡的？
Wait.
別著急
Why won't you answer?
喂！為甚麼不說話？
Show me your ID card, show me!
我讓你拿身份證來看一下
Or I'll charge you for attacking an officer.
現在告你襲警
Hands up! Don't move! Hands up!
舉起手別動！舉高手！
Of course not like that.
當然不是
Hands on the wall; spread your legs.
雙手爬牆上，劈開腿
Like this.
這樣的
Of course not! You're too gentle.
當然不是！哪有這麼斯文的？
Like this; left, then right...
這樣，左翻右翻…
Did you bring it?
有沒有帶東西呀？
That's not patting down.
喂！你這個不是搜身
You're copping a feel.
是體檢
You do it, then, if you're so smart.
那你搜，你這麼能幹
Wearing all those bright colors.
穿的五顏六色的
So improper...
鬼五馬六…
and without a burn...
沒屁股…
Are you done fooling around?
甚麼事呀？玩夠沒有
Who are you calling a burn?
誰沒屁股？
Why am I a bum?
我怎麼沒屁股？
What are you saying?
你說甚麼呀？
Because I went to jail in Malaysia for you.
因為我替你去馬來西亞坐了幾年牢
They whipped me until my burn bled.
讓人用藤打到屁股開花
Without a bum.
沒屁股
Watch what you say.
口無遮攔
Don't think anyone in a uniform is a cop,
不要以為穿著警服就是警察
anyone in designer brands is a celebrity.
穿名牌就是名人啊！
No matter what we wear, we're robbers!
我們穿甚麼都是賊
- We're scumbags!     - About that...
-都是混蛋  -那件事…
You're a scumbag who betrays his buddies.
你是一個不管兄弟的混蛋
About that...
那件事…
Don't talk about that again.   I don't want to listen.
你不要再跟我說那件事，我不想聽
You can say what you want.   But I can't say anything?
你說甚麼都可以，我說就不行呀？
Don't talk to me any more.   I don't want to listen!
你不要再跟我說，我不想聽！
You can talk, I cannot.
你說就行，我說就不行
Yes! You can't accept that?
是！你不服氣啊？
You want to be a robber?
做賊是吧？
You want to be a scumbag?
混蛋是吧！
We're going to rob that transport truck.
我們現在就去等那輛運屍車
We're full, let's go!
人齊了，開車！
人齊開車
Don't leave anything behind!
別落了東西！
You don't know you've left it until you need it.
落東西是落了才知道落了的
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx150\fscy150\an2\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H00AAFF&\3c&H000000&\pos(130,65)\fry-20\frz5\fad(0,0)}King Among Craftsmen
All right!
好！
Let's.
出發！
Hey!
喂！
Roger that! Wrong button, sir!
收到！按錯鍵了
Let's go.
出發
Oh Shit!
糟糕！
Car!
有車呀
Of course; we're on a road. Idiot.
馬路上當然有車啦，笨蛋
Dammit! Son, put on your seat belt!
糟了，兒子！安全帶！
I can eat noodles, right?
吃麵可以吧？
Yes...
是…
See?
看到啦
I told you so.
我早說啦
When you're in a uniform, in a police van,
穿著警服，開著警車
everyone thinks you're a cop.
是人都當你是警察啦
Yeah!
Yeah !
Let's.
出發！
It's certain death ahead.
前面死路一條
If anything happens there's no going back.
出了事回不了頭哦
Just drive on the road!
哎呀，有路你就開啦
They use this road to transport corpses.
這條路人家用來運屍的
What else would they choose?
不走這種路，走甚麼路？
Of course robbers would take the side roads.
劫匪當然是走歪路的
Yes!
對
Hello, darling!
喂…親愛的！
Do you hear me? Hello...
聽到沒有？喂    喂…
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000000&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(100,220)\fad(0,0)}Beware of Boars
There's no signal.
收不到了
Not even one bar.
一格都收不到
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx200\fscy130\an2\b1\bord0.01\shad0\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HFFFFFF&\1a&H66&\pos(190,120)\frz33\fad(0,0)}無訊號
We're in the right place.
那就對了
Stop!
停車！
There's no signal.
收不到
Stop calling your girl.
同你女人少講幾句
That's good; no signal.
這就對了，收不到就對了
This is a good place to get to work!
這裡就適合動手咯
It's so quiet no one would know if you got killed...
這裡安靜的拖個女人來奸了都沒人知道…
Watch out!
看車呀！
- Who is it?     - Who are they?
-甚麼人？  -甚麼來頭？
Didn't they see what we're wearing?
沒看見我們穿甚麼衣服？
You think Hong Kong cops are just ornaments?
當我們香港警察是擺設？
Go! After them!
開工！
Stop!
停車！
Engine off, drivers license.
熄火駕照
The scumbags are molesting a girl!
這兩個混蛋搞女人！
Don't let them go.
別讓他們走
You want to run? I'll let you run. Run!
想跑？讓你跑！跑啊！
Do you know what you're guilty of?
你知不知道犯甚麼罪呀？
Rape.
搞女人
And you tied her up like that!
還把她綁成這樣
Drat! Where are my glasses?
混蛋！我的眼鏡呢？
I just bought them!
新買的，大哥！
A car is a private place.
車是私人地方
I'm just doing private business in my space.
我在私人地方做私事有甚麼問題呀？
Rape.
搞女人
Scumbag! You're raping a woman!
混蛋！欺負女人！
Sir! Listen to me.
警長！聽我說
We are cops, we cannot punish them ourselves...
我們是警察，不可以濫用私刑…
We are cops, we cannot punish them ourselves.
我們是警察，我們不可以濫用私刑
Listen, Miss...
小姐你聽我說…
We're... don't be afraid!
我…別怕，我們是…
We're cops, you'll be fine!
我們是警察，沒事的！
It's useless to bring us in.
抓我們回去沒用的
According to psychological studies,
根據心理學的統計被人性侵犯的女受害人
87% of women victims won't press charges.
有87 ％都選擇息事寧人
Save your strength.
別浪費力氣啦！
You'll never be able to open a file on us.
你們也開不了檔案啦！
You'll have to let us go.
一會兒還不是放人
Let us go, damn cops!
放了我們啦，死警察！
Are you cops stupid?
你們是不是傻啊？
Shut up!
別吵啦！
Hello? Police?
喂，是不是999報案中心呀？
I'm Kong Dai Hoi.
我叫做江大海
My m is z60020s(2)
我身份證號碼是2600206(2)
I'm Leung Tin C991733(3).
梁天，C991733(3)
Our car registration...
車牌號碼
Our car registration is KD1813.
我們車牌是KD1813
We're on Ching Yau Road,
我們在牛潭尾清悠路
Ngau Tarn Mei, Lamp post PA36.
我們的燈柱是PA36號
We raped a girl here.
我們在這裡強姦了一位少女
Send someone to arrest us now, Okay?   Thank you!
快點派人來抓我們，好不好？謝謝你
This is all wrong.
這樣不合規矩
Do you think we're real cops?
你以為我們真是警察？
We're robbers.
我們是賊啊
Why is it wrong?   This is the only right way.
怎麼不合規矩？這樣才合規矩
Whatever! Up to you.
隨便！聽你的！
Come, let's swap.
來…大家交換
Put his in your mouth, yours in his mouth.
你含他的，他含你的
That makes it fun!
這就好玩！
Boars here will bite your wee.
這裡很多野豬咬小弟弟
East L, what are you doing?
阿東你幹甚麼？
Poor girl, she's shivering.
渾身發抖，好慘呀！
Let's go! We've called the cops!
走啦！報了警啦！
Let's go, don't look for trouble.
走啦，不要找麻煩啦！
Lady, don't be afraid!
妹妹！不要害怕呀！
Sue them out of house and home!
告到他們傾家蕩產！
Are you coming yet?
還捨不得走啊？
She's not your daughter!
又不是你女兒！
My colleagues will come soon; be brave!
我的同事很快就來，勇敢點
Be brave!
勇敢點！
Thank you!
謝謝！
She was taken by two guys
這女孩賣雪糕的時候
while selling ice cream.
被這兩個傢伙給綁架啦
At this hour?
這麼晚了賣雪糕？
It's hard to make a living.
賺錢不容易呀！
You know so much, were you flirting with her?
知道的這麼多？泡妞啊？
Are you blind?
你瞎了你
I really can't see without my glasses.
沒有眼鏡真的看不見
How will you drive?
那你怎麼開車啊？
I'll look for them.
我找找
Hey! We've called the cops!
喂！報警了！
I have spares.
有後備的，還有一副
Hurry!
快點
We've called the cops! Hurry!
報警了！快點
Let's.
開車
Sir, the registration number is KD1813,
莊警官，車牌KD1813
the car reported in the rape case.
是接報強姦案發生的車輛
Miss, don't be afraid!   We are police officers!
小姐，你不要怕！我們是警察
We're hereto help you.
我們是來幫你的
Don't be afraid!
你不用怕呀！
Can you please tell us what just happened?
你能不能告訴我剛剛發生甚麼事？
Sir...
徐警官
The suspects could have left these...
可能是疑犯留下的
It's mine!
是我的！
The girl said, a police car came by
那個女孩兒說，有輛警車經過
and officers helped her.
有幾個警察救了他
When the incident occurred
事發的時候
no patrol cars were on duty in this area.
這個區根本沒警車巡邏
The only possibility is, that police car is a fake.
唯一的可能是，這輛警車是假的
They reported it with the suspects' phone.
他們用疑犯的手機報案
Clearly they want to hide their identities.
很明顯是想隱瞞他們的身份
Therefore, the policemen were also fake.
所以，這幾個警察也是假的
He remembers to clean out their wallets; that's A!
救人不忘劫錢包，這個是A
Black cable ties, Giantlok GT630HD,
黑色塑膠束帶，GT630HD
9mm, 79.4kg tensile strength.
9毫米，拉力79.4公斤
First choice of first-rate technicians; that's B!
是有要求的技工的首選，是B !
Is a dried moist wipe still a moist wipe? It's C!
乾了的濕紙巾還是不是濕紙巾？是C
These glasses should belong to D!
這副眼鏡應該就是D的！
These are the bad guys who stole the parts
他們就是在車場偷零件
built the EU and impersonated cops:
改警車，扮警察
A, B, C and D!
意圖不軌的ABCD !
It looks like they've completed their EU
看來，他們的車已經組裝好！
and they've begun their mission!
還開始動手了…
But why did they save her
但是為甚麼他們要救這個女孩
and call the cops?
還要報警呢？
- Police beat me up!     - Shut up!
-警察打人啊！  -閉嘴
Sir, they rescued the girl
有人救了這個女孩
but stole, and used their own punishment.
不過濫用私刑，盜竊
And impersonated policemen.
還自稱警察
So, note it down.
那你就記下來
You want to be a hero again?
又想做英雄
What's the difference between a hero and a cop?
記不記得英雄和警察有甚麼分別？
Cops must abide by the law.
警察要守紀律
Heroes don't have to.
英雄不用
Cops earn a salary, they're employee.
警察有薪水，是打工的
Heroes don't!
英雄沒薪水
They are mostly bosses,
多數都是老闆
like Iron Man.
就是Iron Man那種！
Be a boss before you learn to be a hero.
當了老闆再學人當英雄
Superman is not a boss.
不過超人也不是老闆
He wears his underpants outside his clothes.
超人呢，內褲穿在外面的！
We'll each take up four lanes!
我們一人霸四條球道！
The chicken wings smell great.
雞翼很香啊
- Thank you, Boss!     - So wasteful.
-多謝老闆！  -這麼浪費！
That's not wasteful!
這個不叫浪費
Wasteful is throwing money into the sea.
錢扔進大海叫浪費
We're consuming, albeit extravagantly.
現在叫消費，還能耍威風
Thank you!
多謝！
Hey! That's not for you.
喂！這個不是給你的
It's for you to pay a salary to my buddy
是讓你發薪水給我兄弟
and to buy back his watch!
還有贖回他的表
Sure, no problem!
行，沒問題
Crazy B, it's payday-
阿寶，發薪水
Thank you!
謝謝
Put your watch on.
先把表戴上
Thank you! Enjoy yourselves.
多謝！慢慢玩
Everyone has always cussed me out.
半輩子都被人罵老祖宗
That's the first time I've been thanked! Cool!
第一次有人跟我說謝謝！爽
Cool.
爽啊！
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx130\fscy130\an2\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000066&\3c&H000000&\pos(300,270)\fad(0,0)}Surprisingly Awesome Skills
There is no signal here.
這裡沒有網路覆蓋的
They've been here...
他們又來過這裡
captured two bad guys, and rescued a girl.
還抓了兩個賊，救了個女孩
I believe, they were planning to make a move here.
我相信，他們應該打算在這附近動手
They stole police car parts
他們偷警車零件
but not a whole EU
造假警車卻不整輛偷
to avoid police attention.
因為不想引起警方注意
I order noodles but offer me rice.
要炒麵給炒飯
You can't even get a takeout order right.
連外賣都貨不對辦
Robbing while dressed as a policeman,
扮警察打劫
like a wrong takeout order,
就和貨不對辦的外賣一樣
is a very serious crime!
罪大惡極
I am a policeman. I must catch robbers!
我是警察，就要抓賊
Anything goes wrong, it's every man for himself.
出了事各安天命誰都不救
No! I won't let anything happen to my buddies.
胡說！我不會讓我的兄弟出事的
I'm a very fair man.
我這個人最公道
I decide when things are right or wrong,
我說對就對，我說錯就錯
Money is first priority in a robbery.
打劫當然錢最大
I support you this time.
這次我挺你
- Stop horsing around.     - Aren't you in this?
-喂！不要鬧啦！  -你不玩？
No, I'm not; why?
我不玩啦，幹甚麼啊？
- Real guns? You have real guns?     - What?
-真槍？你拿真槍？  -做甚麼啊
- Why did you bring a real gun?     - Go away!
-你為甚麼拿支真槍來？  -走開
The corpse transport truck.
運屍車…
Where did you get real guns from?
哪裡來的真槍？
Come on, let's go!
走啦，動手啦！
Hands on your head.
手放在頭上
Don't move!
不許動！
Turn off the ignition!
熄火停車！
Sir, how can I do that and not move?
不動怎麼熄火啊？
You speak Cantonese well, friend.
你廣東話說的很好啊，朋友
I was just joking.
開個玩笑
We suspect there are explosives in your truck.
現在懷疑你車裡有爆炸品
Open the back door.
開後車門
Okay...
Okay…
- What are you doing?     - What is that?
-幹甚麼！  -幹甚麼？甚麼東西
Why are you opening the door?
開門幹甚麼？
To open the back door for you.
我開門給你
Give me the key, I'll open it.
拿鑰匙來，我們開
Okay...
Okay…
What are you doing? Freeze! What is that?
喂！幹甚麼，不許動！甚麼東西？
Bring it out slowly.
慢慢拿出來！慢慢
It's a samosa, sir.
這是咖哩角
It's delicious.
很好吃的
Have you eaten dinner, sir?
你吃東西了嗎？
Reach out.
拿出來
Try some.
試一下呀
Big F... Sergeant.
阿發呀…警長
It's quite good.
味道不錯
I can't take it when you're holding on.
你捏住我怎麼拿
It's delicious.
很好吃的
Curry is their specialty.
咖哩他們真是拿手
Do you have any more?
還有沒有
Bring them all out.
全部拿出來
That's all I have.
就這幾塊了
- My daughter made them.     - Give it back.
-我女兒親手做的  -還給人家啦
My colleague will take over.
我的夥計來接手
They'll just check the license. Calm down!
查完牌就會走，鎮定點！
Hands on your heads, don't move!
手放在頭上，不許動！
We suspect you have explosives in your truck.
現在懷疑你後車廂有爆炸品
What shall we do? Someone is coming.
大哥，有人來了現在怎麼辦？
Do we let them go?
放不放他們
Let them go? Get moving!
還放？動手啦！
Kill them!
殺他們！
No policemen use AK-47s.
哪有警察用AK-47 的？
They're not real cops, idiot!
就是不是真警察咯，笨蛋
We're thinking the same thing!
跟我們撞橋！
Go in!
上去
Move the body out!
搬屍體下來！
Roger that!
收到
On your 12.
十二點方向
He's running! Shoot him!
想跑？射他！
One is not dead yet.
還有一個沒死
Faking death? Shoot him!
裝死？射他！
Three...
三！
Let's go... Johnny T!
走啦！杜！
Are we full?
人齊了沒有？
We're full, let's go!
人齊開車啦！
Sit tight!
坐穩啊！
It's gone bad!
出事啦…
How many died?
死了幾個呀？
Did you see that? Just now...
你有沒有看見剛才…
Done!
搞定！
I told you so!
我早說啦！
If I had not insisted on real guns,
要不是我堅持拿支真搶
you'd all be dead.
你們都死了
We're rich!
這次發達啦！
This corpse is all swollen.
你看這具屍漲鼓鼓的
There must be a lot of money.
一定好多錢
Oh, no! They're all dead...
糟糕啦！全死光啦…
What do we do with the kid?
小孩怎麼辦…
We're finished... oh, no.
完蛋…糟糕了
- What do we do?     - We're finished... oh, no.
-現在怎麼辦？  -完蛋…糟糕了
What do we do with the kid?
這小孩怎麼辦…
What do we do? They're all dead.
現在怎麼辦？死光啦
Don't panic! One step at a time.
不要亂，一樣一樣來
What do we do with the kid?
這小孩怎麼辦…
Did you seen that?
你看沒看到啊？
East L, pull over.
阿東先把車停在路邊
- They're all dead!     - Don't panic!
-全部死光了！  -不要亂
One step at a time. Listen to me.
一樣一樣來！聽我說
- Pull over.     - Okay...
-把車停在路邊！  -好好好
- Don't panic! One step at a time.     - Okay...
-不要亂！一樣一樣來！  -好好好
Stop!
停車
Fine; which crisis shall we settle first?
好！說！你們想解決哪件事先
What do we do with the kid?
這小孩怎麼辦呀？
You decide!
你拿主意呀！
You had a part in bringing her here.
你也有份帶她回來的
I ran out to rescue you,
我是衝出去救你
I didn't think you would bring her in here!
我沒想到你會抱她上車的嘛，老大！
Her parents are dead!
她老爸老媽死了！
That's very sad!
很可憐的！
What can we do about that? Crazy B!
那我們又能怎麼樣呢？阿寶
How about this!
這樣吧！
You adopt her.
你收養她
Call her your daughter.
認她做女兒啦！
She'll have your last name,
她跟你姓
and be a robber on our team,
以後跟著我們做賊這樣
okay?
好不好？好不好？
Open the door!
開門
What are you doing?
喂，阿寶，不要亂來啊！
You're always like this.
一輩子都是這個臭德行
- Crazy B!     - Money is not everything.
-阿寶！  -錢不是萬能
Where are you going?
你去哪兒啊？
You're a beast.
沒人性
Wait here for the bus.
在這兒等巴士
Where is Daddy?
爸爸呢？
There are no buses at this hour.
這麼晚哪有巴士啊…
Calm down!
先冷靜點！
Where is my corpse?
我的屍體呢？
I think the cops took it.
好像被那些警察搶走啦！
Calm down!
先冷靜點
Where is my girl?
我女人呢？
I think the cops took her, too!
好像也被那些警察搶走啦！
I got it, East L!
行了，阿東！
Don't panic! One step at a time.
不要亂，一樣一樣來！
Oh, no! They're all dead!
糟糕啦！全死光啦！
Was this your idea?
橋段是你想出來的？
East L, I got it! Come on down...
阿東，行！你下來！下來…
This was your idea. Tell us what to do now.
你想出來的，說怎麼辦啊
Here... have a smoke.
來…先抽口煙
- Have a smoke!     - You're smoking?
-抽口煙！  -你還抽口煙？
So many people are dead and you're smoking?
現在死了這麼多人，你還抽口煙？
I'm not in the mood.
我就抽不了
Give me your phone.
把電話給我
Why?
為甚麼要把電話給你
Someone is dead, right?
死人了嘛？
I'm calling the police!
打999咯！
They'll find out who called.
警察會查到的
I know, call from a phone booth.
我有辦法，去電話亭打
Guaranteed to be untraceable.
保證查不到
Give me a coin.
給我個硬幣
I didn't bring any money.
沒帶錢出來
Johnny T, give me a dollar.
阿杜，給一塊硬幣！
East L, look who is it?
東，你看看是誰？
It's Johnny T.
阿杜啊
No, it's not.
不是啊
You idiots.
你們兩個笨賊
Emergency calls are free.
打999，不用錢
Crazy B! Why did you bring the kid back?
寶！你為甚麼又抱了個小孩回來？
First a woman, and now the kid again.
多了個女人，你又抱個小孩回來
What is wrong with you guys!
有沒有搞錯呀？
We're finished! Not only is someone dead.
完啦！現在不但死了人
Now we have a...
這裡又多一個…
there's a kid...
又多一個小孩…
Don't panic! One step at a time.
不要亂！一樣一樣來！
First, tie her up.
先綁住她！
You're finished!
你們完蛋了！
They must come back to save me...
他們一定回來救我…
Now what?
那現在怎麼辦呀？
We've tied her up!
綁住她啦！
What's next? We're all here.
然後怎麼辦？我們人齊了
You, Big L, me, the corpse...
你，阿發，我，這具屍…
Where's Johnny T?
阿杜呢？
Police! Don't move! Raise your hands!
警察！別動舉起手
We're thinking the same thing!
跟我們撞橋！
How did this happen?
怎麼會這樣
It's the EU!
衝鋒車
Here, Crazy B! East L, drive!
寶！阿東，開車
Auntie!
嬸嬸啊！
This is my bicycle,
這單車是我的
and this is my lunchbox!
這個盒飯也是我的！
You're crazy.
神經病
Of course I know Ming's bicycle.
明仔的單車我怎麼會認錯
I'm a policeman.
我是警察
I need the bicycle to catch a robber.
我需要單車去捉賊
Ming, you became a policeman!
明仔，原來你當警察了
Mommy has waited so long for this!
老媽等了很久啦！
Excuse me! You have the wrong person.
不好意思！我想你認錯人啦
I'm not Ming.
我不是明仔
That's nuts, surely Mommy recognizes you.
神經，明仔老媽怎麼會認錯呢？
Don't be afraid.
不用怕
They're hunting wild boar.
打野豬呢
It's right to kill them.
打死他們就對啦
Ming.
明仔
You won't get it with just one shot.
一槍打不死
Aim at the solar plexus, double tap.
對準太陽穴，雙連擊
Excuse me...
不好意思，打擾啦
Where are you going, Ming?
明仔你去哪啊？
Calm down! Don't hit my girl.
冷靜！不要打到我女人
Calm down...
冷靜 冷靜 冷靜…
- Calm down...     - Let me die.
-冷靜冷靜冷靜…  -讓我死
Let me die.
讓我死
Don't move; they're gone.
不要動，他們走了
Kill me with one shot.
一槍打死我
He's gone, after him!
跑了，快點追！
Drive over there!
開車上去！
No way...
不會吧…
Why?
上去幹甚麼？
Be serious...
不好玩啦…
- Just go! Don't ask!     - You're nuts.
-上去啦！還問？  -神經
Is anyone there?
有沒有人呀？
If not, I'm requisitioning your bicycle!
沒人，我徵用你的單車啦
Without everyone, we can't go.
人不齊，車也不能開
What do we do now?
現在怎麼辦啊！
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000000&\3c&HFFFF77&\pos(140,10)\fad(500,0)}Johnny T
answer?
Johnny T, how are you doing?
阿杜你怎麼樣？
How's my buddy?
我的兄弟怎樣
I think you have my stuff...
你好像拿錯我的東西啦
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000000&\3c&HFFFF77&\pos(140,10)\fad(500,0)}Johnny T
answer?
I know.
有辦法
Get them nervous.
讓他們緊張
We'll regain the initiative.
我們奪回主動權
No... Crazy B...
不是啊，阿寶
I want to say something.
我想說件事
Have you thought about
你有沒有想過
why we're doing all this work?
我們做這麼多事為了甚麼？
It's for the money! Right?
我們為錢嘛！是不是？
Why else if not for money?
我們不是為錢我們為甚麼？
You can't do this to your buddies.
做兄弟不可以這樣的！
We must, if we're doing a major job!
做大事當然是這樣！
How long have we waited for this day?
我們等這一天等了多久了？
Every big job has collateral damage.
做大事肯定有人會犧牲
As he says,
他自己說的
in robbery, cash is king.
打劫錢最大
Nothing else matters.   Every man for himself.
有甚麼事甚麼都不理，各安天命
He got onto the wrong vehicle.
現在他錯上了賊車
Those robbers all have AK's.   They're beasts!
那些賊個個都有AK，沒人性的！
They kill everyone in sight!
見人就殺！
Johnny T may already be killed.
阿杜可能現在被他們殺了
Why are we looking for him?
我們找他幹甚麼？
To get back another corpse?
再找一具屍回來呀？
No!
不行！
I must see him, dead or alive.
生我要見人，死我要見屍
If we go, we'll all be dead!   Don't you understand?
去了我們自己都變成屍！你知不知道呀
We only have these two old toys.
我們就兩支這種破玩意
But every one of them has an AK!
人家每支都是AK啊！
Don't mind him, drive!
阿東別理他，開車！
In this situation, I definitely will not drive.
現在這種情況我一定不會開車
Not driving!
不開！
Now what?
現在甚麼意思
I only obey you two.
就是聽你們倆的
I'm not your buddy.
我不是你們的兄弟
My words carry no weight, correct?
我沒話語權是不是
I say, drive!
我說要開車！
- Drive!     - Not driving!
-開車！  -不開！
Not driving!
不開車！
- Drive!     - No.
-開！你開不開車？  -不開！
Not driving...
不可以開車…
You must not leave your buddy.
不可以扔下兄弟不管！
Not driving!
不開！
- Drive!     - Not driving!
-你開不開車？  -不開！
Drive!
開！
I want to pee...
我想尿尿呀…
Take her to pee.
你帶她尿尿
I'm going, too.
我也去
Can you drive?
你會不會開車？
Answer me, can you drive?
我問你會不會開車啊？
Get my girl on the phone!
叫我女人來聽！
- Big F... what are you doing?     - Can't you hear me?
-發…你幹甚麼？  -是不是聽不到？
Get away!
走開啊！
Get her on the phone!
叫她來聽！
Go!
開車！
Big F!
發！
Our buddies are gone, the money is gone.
兄弟沒了，錢沒了！
My glasses are gone! Everything is gone!
眼鏡也沒了，甚麼都沒了
I quit!
我不玩啦！
Crazy B, I quit!
阿寶，我不玩啦！
I really need to pee.
我要尿尿
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000000&\3c&HFFFF77&\pos(170,10)\fad(0,0)}Johnny T
answer?
Just pee here!
你在這兒尿就行啦！
Kill me...
殺了我…
Kill me!
殺了我！
What are you waiting for?
等甚麼？
Calm down!
冷靜一點！
- Too scared?     - Calm down.
-不夠膽？  -冷靜點
- Kill me!     - Calm down!
-殺了我！  -冷靜點呀
Where are they?
他們在哪裡？
Stop asking!
你不要再問啦！
The baby I'm carrying is not yours.
肚子裡的孩子不是你的
Whose is it?
是誰的
I know! Fung's!
我知道啦，阿鋒！
No, Jack's!
不是！傑克的！
It's not Fung,
不是阿鋒
and not Jack.
也不是傑克
Robert's!
羅拔的！
I know.
我知道了
Robert the barbecued meat man!
切叉燒那個羅拔！
I'm going to chop him up!
我砍死他！
It's not Barbecue Robert.
不是叉燒羅拔
- Give it to me.     - It's your cousin Robert.
-交給我  -是你表哥羅拔
Damn it.
該死的
Yes! The baby is Robert's!
是啊！孩子是羅拔的！
Don't call me anymore!
你別再打來！
Who is Robert?
誰是羅拔？
His cousin.
他表哥
Kill me!
殺了我！
Please...
我求你…
So, where are we going?
去哪裡？到底去哪裡？
I don't think you have plan.
我看你也不知道是不是
You never had an exit strategy.
你們打劫之後，沒想過怎樣離開
I know a smuggler's tunnel under a drainage pipe.
我知道有個排水渠下面掘了一條走私隧道
I'll guide you through it
我帶你走
but you must let me go.
但你放了我
We'll split the money between us.
錢咱倆平分
What did we bump into? Hey...
撞到甚麼了？喂…
Did we run over someone?
看看是不是撞到人了？
Stop!
停車！
It's a dog!
狗！
Back up and check.
倒車回去看看
See if we ran over anyone.
看看是不是撞到人了
If so, we're in deep trouble.
撞到人就麻煩了
So what if we run over someone?
撞到人又怎麼樣？
Will you call the police?
你去報警嗎？
Of course we'll call the police!
報警！當然報警！
What else can we do?
不然怎麼辦？
Go back... I told you to back up!
回去…我叫你倒車啊！
It's no big deal to us robbers if someone dies.
我們做賊的死一個半個又能怎樣
Didn't you say there's collateral damage?
你不是說幹大事的就一定有犧性嗎？
See how unlucky you are.
你看你多倒霉
Your girl don't want you, buddies abandon you.
女人不要你，兄弟不管你
Yes! That is most unlucky!
是啊！真是倒霉透了！
But there's nothing we can do!
沒辦法啦！
Money buys you buddies and girls, right?
有錢有兄弟，沒錢沒女人，是吧
As they say
正所謂
in this business we only trust money.
出來混的只信一個錢字
You must understand that. Don't be naive.
你不會不明白吧？這麼天真
Have money, and women know you're a man.
女人，有錢他們就認你是男人
If no money, they don't treat you like a human.
沒錢就把你不當人，對不對？
All right!
好呀！
Vent your hatred, kill me!
洩你的心頭之恨打死我
I want to die.
我也想死
Why don't we make a bet before I die.
不如死之前賭一把
I'll bet you won't find your girl.
我賭你一定找不到你的女人
I'll Win!
我贏啊！
Give me a bullet.
你送一顆子彈給我
Remember to hit my head.
記住打我頭
Make it accurate! Make no mistakes!
記住，打準一點不要打錯！
Shoot me in the head!
打我頭！
Get my girl on the phone, Now!
叫我女人聽電話，立刻
Call her.
對啊
Auntie, are you okay?
嬸嬸，你怎麼樣啊？
Mommy's fine.
老媽沒事
Ming, were you frightened by the wild boar?
明仔有沒有被那些野豬嚇倒啊？
Let me take you to the hospital.
我先送你去醫院
The pickles will rot at home.
酸菜在家裡會發臭的
I want to go home.
我要回家
Robbers will run if I don't catch them.
賊不抓會跑的
After take you to hospital,
我送你去了醫院
I'll go catch the robber, come on!
我還要去抓賊，來啦！
If you won't eat this, you won't go.
你不吃，不能走
What is this?
這是甚麼？
Ming, you are right, I am wrong.
明仔對，老媽不對
Police must catch robbers.
警察要抓賊的嘛
Right?
是不是
Don't worry about me!
你不要管老媽啦！
Go catch the robbers!
你去抓賊啦！
I'm fine.
我沒事的
Cop or robber
你是警察還是賊
you're still my good boy!
明仔都是老媽的乖孩子！
Rotten or not, it's still a pickle!
這酸菜臭不臭都是酸菜！
Underpants inside or outside, Superman is Superman!
底褲穿在外面還是裡面，超人就是超人
I'll take you home.
我先送你回家
The pickle really is rotten.
酸菜真的是臭了！
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000000&\3c&HFFFF77&\pos(140,10)\fad(500,0)}Johnny T
Connecting...
Hang up on me again and I'll kill him.
你再掛我線我就殺了他
Let my buddy go.
放了我兄弟
We'll give you your girl and the corpse.
你女人和屍體都可以給你
That parking lot we just passed,
就是剛才經過的那個停車場
we'll exchange hostages there.
我們在那兒交換人質
Why would I trust you?
我憑甚麼要信你
Hostage exchanges are all about trust.
交換人質這種事，大家都要講個信字
I dare to gamble! So should you!
我敢賭！你也要賭！
I saw you kill many people.
我見過你殺了很多人
For my buddy's sake I trust you.
為了我兄弟，我相信你
For a corpse and a girl, do you dare gamble?
為了一具屍體和女人，敢不敢賭
I must prove that you are wrong.
我要證明給你看你是錯的
You're unlucky but I'm not.
你倒霉我不倒霉
Your girl is not my girl.
你女人不是我女人
My girl would never betray me.
我女人是不會出賣我的
Fine! I trust you!
好！我信你！
Scumbag! It's my turn to hang up on you.
混蛋！這次輪到我掛你電話
Don't be afraid, calm down, Miss.
小姐，鎮定點，你不用怕
- So... what do you do?     - I sell ice cream.
-對啦，你是做甚麼的？  -我賣雪糕的
Why are you selling ice cream so late at night?
怎麼你這麼晚還賣雪糕呢？
Tonight is Halloween!
今天萬聖節
Some people stay out really late.
有的人玩到很晚
It's great for my business!
所以生意還是挺好的
I must go now.
我先走啦
Where are you going? I'll give you a lift.
你去哪裡，我送你吧？
You ask where I'm going, I really don't know.
你問我去哪裡，我真不知道自己想去哪裡
I've bumbled through half my life.
稀里糊塗過了半輩子
I follow my buddies wherever they go.
兄弟們去哪裡，我就跟他們去哪裡
Now I'm left all alone.
現在只剩下我自己一個人
I really don't know where to go.
我真的不知道去哪裡
My glasses are gone, I can't see.
眼鏡又沒了，又看不見
Calm down, don't be afraid!
鎮定，不用怕
Thank you, Officer!
謝謝！
Stop!
停車！
I know you're not Ming...
我知道你不是明仔
If not for the damned wild boars.
如果不是那幾隻死野豬
Ming would be your age now.
我的明仔可能已經像你那麼大啦…
He may have become policeman, too.
他可能都做警察
He may bring me home before
可能他都會選擇先送我這個瘋婆子回家
catching robbers, too.
而不是去捉賊
Why are you still standing here?
你還站在這裡幹甚麼啊？
Go catch robbers!
還不去捉賊？
Goodbye sir.
再見
I warn you
我警告你
they are human!
這是人啊！
You're not concerned your buddy has died.
自己兄弟死了你都不關心
Yet you would worry about a stranger.
陌生人倒反而關心起來
Be a true bad guy, then!
做壞人你做到底啊！
Police! Stop!
警察！停車！
Stop!
停車！
Watch what you're doing...
你別亂來
Give me your gun!
把槍給我
Why would I give you my gun?
我為甚麼要把槍給你
Don't come over...
別過來…
Give me your gun!
把槍給我
_.
我開槍了！
Why would I give you my gun?
我為甚麼要把槍給你
I came to rob
我是打劫
but didn't get anything.   I didn't kill anyone.
但是我甚麼都沒打劫到，我又沒殺人
The bitch in the minibus is a killer.
車裡那個八婆才殺人
Give me your gun.
把槍給我
Why would I do that?
我為甚麼要把槍給你呀？
Give me your gun!
給我
What? So what if you're police?
幹甚麼，警察怎麼啦
I must give you my gun?
我就要把槍給你啊
Do cops trump everything else?
警察了不起啊
Get in!
上車
You don't go catch robbers, but instead, catch me?
那些賊你怎麼不去抓？抓我？
Get in!
上車
Remember, I saved your life!
你記住，是我救你的！
Get in! We'll talk at the station!
上車，回警局再說！
Girls cannot go into the men's restroom.
女孩不能進男廁的
It's late, it doesn't matter.?
這麼晚了，廁所哪有分男女的
I need to pee.
先尿泡尿
He may be tied up, but he needs to shut up.
這個小子綁成那樣還那麼多話
After I find my girl,
等我找到我女人之後
I will shoot him in the mouth
就一槍打爆他的嘴
and then shoot him in the head.
再一槍打爆他的頭
Hold on!
撐住啊！
Just ignore what that scumbag says.
大哥，不要理那個混蛋說的話
You're nuts, why would I listen to him?
神經我怎麼會理他呀？
It's his bad luck he was dumped.
他被女人甩是他倒楣嘛
That really is unlucky.
真的是挺倒楣的
She got herself pregnant
自己女人被別人搞大肚子
with his cousin.
而且還是他表哥搞的
I've thought it through.
我想清楚了
My girl would never betray me.
我女人是不會出賣我的
Come find my girl with me.
跟我去找我女人
My princess was taken by bad guys...
我的公主被壞人帶走了
Don't move.
別動
I made you to lose Princess,
叔叔害你不見了公主
so I'll make you one.
叔叔做一個給你
You're a princess!
你就是公主啦！
I have a buddy who
我有個兄弟
wants others to give him two thumbs up always.
整天都很想有人向他豎大拇指
Where's my police cap?
喂，我的警帽呢？
You weren't wearing one just now...
你剛才沒戴帽子…
Where's my police cap?
我的警帽呢？
You're asking me?
你問我幹甚麼？
Sir, it doesn't help to arrest me.
你抓我沒用的
Ow, it hurts!
哇！好痛…
Move.
走
You should arrest those scumbags!
要抓就抓那些混蛋啦！
They are inhuman.
他們個個沒人性
Spraying bullets with their AK's.
拿著AK到處亂射
Sit down!
坐下！
Catch those guys!
你抓那些人呀！
They are the robbers!
他們才是大賊啊！
We arrest anyone who commits a crime.
警察辦案，壞事是不分大小
You impersonated police officers
你們扮警察
and made a fake EU.
組裝假衝鋒車
These are serious crimes already.
已經很多條罪
I will take you in now!
我現在送你回警局！
Princess.
小公主
Wait here for the bus.
你在這裡等巴士
Your beard tickles...
鬍子好扎人啊！
Are there buses at this hour?
這麼晚怎麼會有巴士？
I'm going to catch the robbers
警察叔叔去抓壞人
and save my buddies.
去救兄弟
When you get on the bus.
上了巴士之後
Tell the driver
跟司機哥哥說
to go find Mr Policeman.
叫他帶你去找警察叔叔
Don't leave me here!
不要扔下我呀！
Be good!
乖！
Wait bus here.
你在這裡等巴士
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000000&\3c&H88BBDD&\pos(192,200)\fad(0,0)}BAD
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H000000&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(110,10)\fad(1500,2000)}There Are Bad Guys Outside
What time is it...
幾點了…
Did you get fired again?
你又被人炒了啊？
Did I...
我…
Did I ever give you a doll?
我有沒有送過布娃娃給你啊？
I don't remember...
我不記得了
Why are you asking in the middle of the night?
你為甚麼半夜三更問我這件事
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
What kind of doll do you like?
你喜歡甚麼布娃娃
I'll buy it for you.
我買給你呀
Mr Chou, how old am I?
周先生，我幾歲了？
You want to give me a doll'?
還送布娃娃？
22, still my little girl.
二十二歲，還是一個小丫頭
You are decades old, still my old man
你也幾十歲了，一個老傢伙
and still sleeping so late! Get some sleep.
還是這麼晚睡，早點睡吧！
Why is she alone?
那女孩為甚麼在這裡？
Where is Crazy B?
阿寶呢？
Little Girl, where did your jacket come from?
小妹妹，你的衣服哪兒來的？
Hey! Girl!
喂！小妹妹！
Where is that man?
那個人呢？那個人…
The curly-haired policeman.
捲毛那個啊！捲毛警察叔叔！
He said he's going to save his buddies!
他說他去救兄弟啊！
Did you hear that, sir?
你聽見了嗎？
I really cannot go to the station with you!
我真的不能跟你回警局！
I must to save my buddy!
我要救我的兄弟啊！
Please.
麻煩您
I promise you
我答應你
after we take you to the station
送了你到警局之後
we will go save your friend.
我們會去救你的朋友
Little girl, would you like some ice cream?
小妹妹，要不要吃雪糕呀？
Sir, I'm doing great business today.
今天晚上生意真好
I just gave a cone to another policeman.
我剛剛還請了一個警察吃雪糕
And given him back his glasses.
那副眼鏡我已經還給他了
It's him...
是他…
He was confused and couldn't see too well.
看東西看不清楚，傻乎乎！
Now he knows where to go!
他現在知道要去哪兒啦！
Sir! Let me go!
喂！你放我啦！
East L has returned to the team!
阿東都歸隊啦！
After I finish my business I will go in with you.
我搞定我的事後一定跟你回警局
Trust me!
你信我啦！
Can you please take her to the police station?
小姐，能不能幫我送這個小妹妹回警局？
- Okay!     - Thank you!
-嗯！  -謝謝！
"B" saved a little girl.
B救了個小妹妹
"D" saved a rape victim.
D救了個被人非禮的女孩
You are and you saved me.
你是A，救了我
That's right!
就是囉！
I saved you.
我救了你
You should let me go
你應該放我
to save my buddies.
我去救我兄弟
You say you want to save your buddies?
你還說救兄弟
You want to go against those robbers?
你還要對付那些賊呀？
You think this uniform is real?
你以為這制服真的？
It doesn't matter what we wear.
隨便啦，穿甚麼都無所謂！
Trust me this once!
你信我一次啦！
Our last stop will be the police station
最後一站一定是警局
but we can make one stop before that.
不過之前可以多停一站
Thank you, officer!
多謝！
Where do you want to get off?
在哪裡下？
Asshole.
混蛋
Why are the scumbags here?
怎麼這些混蛋在這裡呢？
These are the scumbags.
就是這些混蛋
Watch what you're doing...
不要亂來啊…
They are heavily armed.
他們有重火力
Stay calm...
鎮定…
They won't dare touch us.
他們不敢動我們
We have his girl...
他女人在我們這兒
They have my girl.
我女人在那邊
Don't shoot...
不要開槍
My two buddies!
我兩個兄弟啊！
Grab the girl and the corpse!
搶女搶屍！
What happened?
搞甚麼鬼？
Get up...
起身…
Are you okay?
行不行
Buddy.
兄弟
He is alive...
沒死呀！
Crazy B...
寶哥
Who is this?
這個是誰啊？
Officer Tsui, a real cop.
徐警官，真警察
What happened to him?
他怎麼了？
He's been shot.
他中槍呀
Do you have a dollar?
有沒有一元
Another dollar? What for?
你又找一元，用來做甚麼？
With these injures, call an ambulance.
大哥，傷成這樣打999報警嘛
Emergency calls are free.
打999報警不需要錢的
I can't take you to the police station any more.
我沒法送你們去警局了
The world is so strange...
這個世界真是怪…
Turtle jelly that has no turtle.
龜靈膏沒龜
Milk tea that has no milk.
奶茶沒奶
Bad guys that aren't bad.
壞人不壞
Where will you get off?   Think about it carefully.
這架小巴在哪裡下車，你們自己想清楚
Stop!
停車！
What's wrong?
甚麼事？
The money is not inside the corpse...
那錢沒在屍體裡…
Why didn't you say so sooner?
你不早說？
When I was in the truck
運屍車的時侯
I removed the money...
我已經把錢拿走了…
I am really sorry, buddies!
我真的是很對不起大家
I didn't think you'd risk your lives to for me.
我沒想到大家會不要命回來救我
I sold out my buddies over a woman like that.
為了一個這樣的女人出賣我的兄弟
I'm a scumbag!
我是混蛋！
I am a bastard!
我不是人！
I'm sorry...
對不起啊！
Hey! Hey...
喂！喂…
I'm bastard!
我不是人
I'm a scumbag...
我混蛋啊！
- I'm a scumbag...     - What scumbag?
-我混蛋啊！  -甚麼混蛋
I'm just as much of a scumbag.
我也一樣混蛋
I've made it clear; I'd choose money over you.
我也說了，要錢不要你
Hey, fine... Sit down.
喂！沒事…先坐下
Are you sure?
真的沒事
The money is still with us?
錢還在我這裡？
Yes!
是呀！
I have to pee!
尿尿！
I haven't seen the sunrise in a long time!
很久沒見過日出啦！
I haven't seen Hong Kong in a long time!
很久沒看過香港啦！
I haven't seen so clearly in a long time!
很久看東西沒看得這麼清楚啦
Have you thought out where to go?
那你們想清楚去哪裡了嗎？
Out of my way! Don't block me.
喂！走開啦，不要攔著我啊！
I must stop those robbers!
要去阻止那幫賊嘛
That gang of inhuman beasts
那幫混蛋沒人性的嘛
kills everyone they see.
他們見人就殺
I don't know if I did the right thing,
我不知道這件事做的對不對
but it shouldn't be too wrong.
但是我覺得至少不會太錯
Big F, can you drive?
阿發，你會開車嗎？
Yes! You saved me at such great cost
是啊！你們這麼辛苦救我回來
you're not planning to leave me here, right?
不是不帶我玩吧？
Take me along, I'll be okay.
帶上我，我可以的
You went along with me to be robbers,
我說做賊你們又挺我
but now we're going to catch other robbers.
不過做賊做到要去捉賊
This sounds rather stupid to me.
我自己都覺得有點愚蠢
This whole incident...
這件事呢
sounds a bit stupid.
聽起來是有點愚蠢
And I don't know why, but
不知道為甚麼
somehow it feels so cool.
隱隱約約覺得好像很有型
Faster!
快點呀！
If they get to the campsite, more people will die!
讓他們去到營地死的人就更多啦！
East L, step on it!
東，踩油門啊！
Roger that!
收到
Go, ignore them!
走，別理他！
Hurry, East L!
快點東！
Faster!
快點呀！
These four guns may be rusty
這四支槍雖然生了銹
and not so good on their own
一支不行
but they're vicious when tied together.
但綁在一起還是很猛的！
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
你不早說
What else are you hiding?
還有些甚麼藏著沒拿出來
Also...
還有啊
Shoot! Talk later!
開槍啦！還說？
Your turn; kill!
你來，殺
Shoot it!
射它！
Asshole!
混蛋！
What happened?
怎麼了
We're out of ammo?
沒子彈啦？
- What happened?     - We're all out!
-怎麼了？  -打沒了
Sit tight!
坐穩啦！
Oh Shit.
Oh Shit
Good thing we put in bulletproof glass!
幸好換成了防彈玻璃！
Stop! East L...
煞車！東…
Stop!
停車！
East L...
阿東…
Stop!
停車！
Crash into them!
撞它！
It's flattened!
扁了！
All done!
搞定！
The police cap really is here...
那警察的帽子真是在這兒
They did everything they said.
他們講得出做得到
These four came to turn themselves in
他們四個不止來自首
and brought gifts.
還帶禮物
Five AK'S, Five Type 54'S
五支AK，五支黑星
three shotguns, 236 bullets,
三支霰彈槍，二百三十六發子彈
and five robbers with 172 wounds.
還有五個加起來一百七十二個傷口的悍匪
But most incredibly
最想不到的是
there's also the police cap I lost 16 days ago.
還有我丟了十六天的那頂警帽
This minibus's last stop was the police station
這輛小巴的終點站真的是警局
but they went to the wrong place
可是，送禮都送錯地方
and brought it to the Marine Police Station.
他們送去了水警總部
This is a case of
這件案件的真相是
one gang of police-impersonating robbers
一幫扮警察的賊打劫
running into another gang of police-impersonating robbers.
遇到另一幫扮警察的賊
This gang of fake cops killed many people.
這幫扮警察的賊殺了很多人
That gang of fake cops felt that was wrong
那幫扮警察的賊看不過去
and went to capture this gang of fake cops.
就去抓這幫扮警察的賊
Without that gang of fake cops
如果沒那幫扮警察的賊
we would never have caught this gang of fake cops.
我們根本抓不到這幫扮警察的賊
I'm not sure what you're saying
我不太知道你說甚麼
but it sounds cool.
不過聽起來很有型
It is cool...
是很有型的…
Four bowling balls and one minibus
四個保齡球，一輛小巴
captured five robbers with AK's.
抓了五個拿AK的賊
Two dead, three seriously injured.
兩死三重傷
It really doesn't matter what one wears.
穿甚麼真的不重要
I've been a gang boss,
我做過老大
and a robber,
做過賊
and impersonated a cop.
還冒充過警察
Whatever one does
甚麼人都好
it's just a job title
就是一個名字
that others call you by.
都是被人叫的
Just like what you wear
就好像穿甚麼
is for others to see.
不過是穿給別人看
With the courage to face yourself
有膽面對自己
what does it matter what you wear?
穿甚麼又有甚麼關係？
The key is to know what you're doing!
最重要是知道自己在做甚麼
"Two thumbs up" is not what others give you
這兩個大拇指不是別人給的
it's what you give yourself!
是自己給自己的！
No matter where he wears his underpants,
內褲穿在外面還是裡面
Superman is still Superman.
超人始終是超人
A dried moist wipe or a moist dry wipe,
乾了的濕紙巾還是濕了的乾紙巾
as long as it believes it can clean things,
只要它相信自己還能擦東西
it is a wipe.
它就是一張好紙巾
Don't think anyone in uniform is a policeman.
不要以為穿著制服就是警察
It doesn't matter what you wear.
穿甚麼根本無所謂！
Angel or devil.
天使還是魔鬼
Devil or angel.
魔鬼還是天使
It depends on how you look at it.
要看你怎麼看了！
Special news report.
特別新聞報導
This morning just after 5 am
今晨五點多
two morning joggers discovered wanted
兩名晨運的市民在南涌一間公廁附近
fugitive and illegal roach farmer Cheung.
發現非法蟑螂養殖場負責人
Po-keung near a public toilet in Nam Chung.
警方通緝犯張寶強
Police describe.
警方引述
Cheung to be very emotionally agitated
他們發現張寶強的時候
when they discovered him.
他情緒相當激動
Cop steals bicycle.
不停大叫警察偷單車
Police rushed to the scene and arrested
警方接報警後，立即趕到現場
this man who turned
當場將這個弄至
Hong Kong upside down.
香港滿城風雨的始作俑者拘捕
Why do people throw trash everywhere?
這些人有甚麼理由亂扔垃圾
Just have a barbecue, damn it!
燒烤就燒烤唄
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx100\fscy100\an9\b1\bord2\shad0\c&H00CCCC&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(380,180)\fad(1000,0)}16 Months Later
Big F, I've wanted to tell you something for years...
阿發，有件事想跟你說十幾年了
Fine, never mind.
行了，不要再說
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx80\fscy80\an1\b1\bord2\shad0\c&HHFF7700&\3c&HFFFFFF&\pos(5,280)\fad(2000,0)}Hong Kong's
South-easternmost
Country Park
near Tai Larn
Correctional Institution
It's about that time you drank pee
你又想說你為了我們去喝尿
and ate roaches for us, right?
吃蟑螂那件事對吧？
How long have you known?
你知道多久了？
A long time...
知道了很久啦
But I didn't tell you
不過不跟你說
to let you feel you owed us.
讓你覺得是你欠我們
It's not about us owing you.
不是甚麼我們欠你的
You're just a scumbag.
你就是個混蛋
A real scumbag!
真是個混蛋
Scumbag...
混蛋…
Lost 7-year-old girl, Tsang Ching-yee, miraculously rescued after two weeks.
失蹤兩周七歲女孩曾靜儀奇蹟獲救
So those weren't her parents.
原來他們不是他老爸老媽
They were kidnappers.
是人販子
So not only did we catch robbers
看來我們不止抓了賊
we even rescued someone.
還救了人呢
At first, if I risk it all to save you
看來，不是我捨命救你
you would have died of a brain hyperemia.
你腦充血死了
No matter what we wear, we are heroes!
我們四個穿甚麼都是英雄
Remember, girl, I saved you.
小妹妹你記住，是我救了你！
Tell her, I rushed out to save you!
你告訴他，是我先衝出去救你的
Tell her, if not for my gun
你告訴他，要不是我的槍
both of you would have been dead.
你們兩個早死了
Without my guns
沒我的槍
you three would have died.
你三個都死了
See who they are thanking.
你看看人家謝謝誰？
Two thumbs up! That's me!
TWO THUMBS UP  啊！我啊！
I taught her that! You tell him...
是我教他的，你告訴他！
I taught you!
是我教你的
Let me tell you,
現在我告訴你
I taught him about "two thumbs up".
TWO THUMPS UP  是我教他的
There is no more 39633 in this world.
這個世界不再有39633
There is only me, Lucifer.
只有一個人叫盧西發！
You can call me Big F.
給面子就叫聲發哥
I'll get off at the intersection.
路口下車
- I want to get off...     - Restricted area.
-下車啊…  -禁區啊
Why didn't you tell me?   We've passed our stop.
你不早說？都過站了！
Get off when you can.
能下就下吧！
I want off! You damned minibus driver!
下車啊…死小巴司機！
I want off...
下車啊…
How would I know that's a restricted area?
我怎麼知道哪是禁區？
I'll tell you.
不知道就告訴你
Don't take the minibus if you can't walk!
走不動就別坐小巴啦！
Take a taxi! Scumbag!
坐出租車啦！混蛋！
My number 39633.
我的警察編號39633
My name is Tsui On Leung.
我叫徐安良，除暴安良的徐安良
Buddies!
兄弟！
I have another idea!
我又想到一個點子！
Tell me if you're okay with it.
聽聽可不可以
I'm okay with it.
我可以的
Do you think you're not unlucky enough?
你是不是還嫌不夠倒楣吧？
Speak! Since we are buddies.
說！既然是兄弟
I, Crazy B, will back you if I can.
我喪寶能挺你就一定挺
What's there to back?
挺甚麼啊？
We don't have the minibus any more.
現在連小巴都沒了
Even if it's full, we have no van to drive.
人齊了也沒車開
My third grand-uncle in Apleichau
我三叔公，在鴨舌洲有隻龍舟
had only a dragonboat; let's turn it into
我們把龍舟改成軍艦
a warship to take back our island.
去搶我們的島回來
This won't be only carrying out justice
這次不止替天行道
we'll be the glory of our nation!
簡直為國增光
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe134\fscx100\fscy100\an8\b0\bord2\shad0\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HFFFFFF&\1a&HFF&\2a&HFF&\4a&HFF&\pos(192,10)\fad(0,0)}喂！別急
痴夢續發
感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感感
感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感感
hey5377880@pchome.com.tw
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝謝
hey5377880@pchome.com.tw
收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收
收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收
收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收
收收
收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收收
hey5377880@pchome.com.tw
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看看
hey5377880@pchome.com.tw
{\fnArial Unicode MS\fe0\fscx130\fscy130\an2\b1\bord0.01\shad0\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HFFFFFF&\2a&HFF&\4a&HFF&\pos(192,260)\fad(0,0)}THE END